<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brain Tumor on Just for your understanding</title>
    <link>/categories/brain-tumor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brain Tumor on Just for your understanding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/brain-tumor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Does your cell line work?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</guid>
      <description>My experience When doing the PhD thesis project, I want to detect the ROS-related genes expression by q-PCR. Nine sets of primers were used but only one of them had a positive result. The left eight genes were negtive in the cell line most colleagues used. It seemed impossible but it happened.
In the beginning, I suspected the primers were not right or in bad quality. Another eight new sets of primers were ordered but I still got negtive result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between macrophage and dendritic cell</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/03/what-is-the-difference-between-macrophage-and-dendritic-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/03/what-is-the-difference-between-macrophage-and-dendritic-cell/</guid>
      <description>ABsTRACT  The mononuclear phagocyte system (MPS) has historically been categorized into monocytes, dendritic cells and macrophages on the basis of functional and phenotypical characteristics. However, considering that these characteristics are often overlapping, the distinction between and classification of these cell types has been challenging.In this Opinion article, we propose a unified nomenclature for the MPS. We suggest that these cells can be classified primarily by their ontogeny and secondarily by their location, function and phenotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain tumor center in USA</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</guid>
      <description>The brain tumor center in the USA is listed in
http://abc2.org/guidance/find-care
1 NCI cancer research center neuro-oncology branch https://ccr.cancer.gov/Neuro-Oncology-Branch
2 Dana Farber Center for neuro-oncology https://www.dana-farber.org/center-for-neuro-oncology/clinical-research-and-trials/
3 Duke University The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center https://tischbraintumorcenter.duke.edu/program-members/
Please find more information about brain tumore ccenter in USA here
When choosing a brain tumor treatment center, consider:
 How many brain tumor patients the center treats each year Whether the center offers access to specialists, such as a neuro-oncologist and radiation oncologist Whether the center is in your insurance plan’s covered network  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem cell in U87</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</guid>
      <description>Are there stem cells in the cell line cultures? Yes, some cell lines have.
U87 is one gliblastoma cell line containing stem cell. You can isolate them following the protocol below.
Lacopino F, Angelucci C, Piacentini R, Biamonte F, Mangiola A, et al. (2014) Isolation of Cancer Stem Cells from Three Human Glioblastoma Cell Lines: Characterization of Two Selected Clones. PLOS ONE 9(8): e105166. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0105166
 All the monolayer growing cell lines, U373 (22–25th passage), U87-MG (52–55th passage) and LI (93–95th passage) were seeded at a density of 100,000 cells/ml, in a defined serum-free medium, DMEM/F12, supplemented with antibiotics (penicillin 100 IU/ml, streptomycin 100 µm/ml), HEPES (10 mM), glutamine (2 mM), glucose (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell apoptosis signaling pathway</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</guid>
      <description>Background I reviewed several manuscripts titled liket &amp;ldquo;XX promotes oxidative stress and induces apoptosis in YY cells&amp;rdquo;.
Here, &amp;ldquo;XX&amp;rdquo; can be any chemical from nature product or synthezed in the lab. &amp;ldquo;YY&amp;rdquo; can be caner cells, nenron cells and various cells. They may be cell lines or primary cells. By combination, hundreds of paper can be produced. How do you evaluate them in the perspective of basic reserch or drug development?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why cancer happens?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</guid>
      <description>The nature of cancer is abnormal proliferation of cells made of our organ, tissue and body.What drives physiology cells into crazy demons? Are genetic facrors or enviroment risks canse the transition of cells from health to disease?
According to modern biological perspective, genome mutation results in the cell transformation.
Cell changes and cancer  All cancers begin in cells. Our bodies are made up of more than a hundred million million (100,000,000,000,000) cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuro-Oncology</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/03/neuro-oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/03/neuro-oncology/</guid>
      <description>Neuro OncologyIt is the officical journal of the Society for Neuro-Oncology and published monthly from Jan.2010.
The current impact factor is 10.091 and 5-year impact factor is 9.053
About the editorKenneth Aldape is the interim editor-in-chief. His research area is genomic and epigenomic alterations in brain tumors, &amp;gt;including glioma and meningioma. We characterize the biology of specific genomic alterations and how they contribute to &amp;gt;the molecular pathogenesis and treatment resistance of aggressive brain tumors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>