<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cancer on Just for your understanding</title>
    <link>/categories/cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cancer on Just for your understanding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences of mitotic slippage for antimicrotubule drug therapy</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/18/consequences-of-mitotic-slippage-for-antimicrotubule-drug-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/18/consequences-of-mitotic-slippage-for-antimicrotubule-drug-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Consequences of mitotic slippage for antimicrotubule drug therapy
Antimitotic agents Microtubule poisons are divided into taxanes and vinca alkaloids depending on how they affect microtubule dynamics. Taxanes are microtubule-stabilising drugs that inhibit the dynamic instability of spindles; examples include commonly-used drugs such as paclitaxel and docetaxel. Vinca alkaloids depolymerise microtubules thereby preventing their attachment to kinetochores; drugs such as vinblastine, vincristine and vinolrelbine fall into this categor
SAC spindle assembly checkpoint The SAC prevents improper chromosome segregation and mitotic exit via inhibition of the anaphase-promoting complex (APC)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Excision Repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/16/base-excision-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/16/base-excision-repair/</guid>
      <description>Glycosylases and lyases. Enzymes that remove bases from DNA
Long-patch pathway Glycosylase action is followed by the endonuclease APE1, which cleaves the polynucleotide chain on the 5′ side. This, in turn, attracts a replication complex that includes DNA polymerase δ/ε and ancillary components. The replication complex performs a short synthesis reaction extending for 2 to 10 nucleotides. The displaced material is removed by the flap endonuclease (FEN1). The enzyme ligase 1 seals the chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error-Prone Repair and Translesion Synthesis</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/16/error-prone-repair-and-translesion-synthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/16/error-prone-repair-and-translesion-synthesis/</guid>
      <description>Damaged DNA that has not been repaired causes prokaryotic DNA polymerase III to stall during replication
  DNA polymerase V (encoded by umuCD) or DNA polymerase IV (encoded by dinB) can synthesize a complement to the damaged strand.
  The DNA synthesized by repair DNA polymerases often has errors in its sequence
  most systems, including uvr-controlled excision repair, do not differ significantly from DNA replication in the frequency of mistakes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/13/dna-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/13/dna-repair/</guid>
      <description>Concept The measured rate of mutation reflects a balance between the number of damaging events occurring in DNA and the number that have been corrected.
The response to damage includes activation and recruitment of repair enzymes; modification of chromatin structure; activation of cell cycle checkpoints; and, in the event of insufficient repair in multicellular organisms, apoptosis
Three type damage  single-base changes : deamination of cytosine to uracil structural distortions/bulky lesions, strand breaks  Direct repair One good example is photoreactivation of pyrimidine dimers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetracycline (Tet) Inducible Expression</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/13/tetracycline-tet-inducible-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/13/tetracycline-tet-inducible-expression/</guid>
      <description>Tet Response Element (TRE) A TRE is 7 repeats of a 19 nucleotide tetracycline operator (tetO) sequence, and is recognized by the tetracycline repressor (tetR). In the endogenous bacterial system, if tetracycline, or one of its analogs like doxycycline, are present, tetR will bind to tetracycline and not to the TRE, permitting transcription.
Tetracycline-dependent promoters are developed by placing a TRE upstream of a minimal promoter.
Tetracycline Off System ( tTA-dependent system) tTA (tetracycline-controlled transactivator) = tetR+VP16</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chromatin-mediated reversible drug tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/a-chromatin-mediated-reversible-drug-tolerant-state-in-cancer-cell-subpopulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/a-chromatin-mediated-reversible-drug-tolerant-state-in-cancer-cell-subpopulations/</guid>
      <description>Citation Sharma, S. V., Lee, D. Y., Li, B., Quinlan, M. P., Takahashi, F., Maheswaran, S., McDermott, U., Azizian, N., Zou, L., Fischbach, M. A., Wong, K. K., Brandstetter, K., Wittner, B., Ramaswamy, S., Classon, M., &amp;amp; Settleman, J. (2010). A chromatin-mediated reversible drug-tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations. Cell, 141(1), 69–80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2010.02.027
Abstract Accumulating evidence implicates heterogeneity within cancer cell populations in the response to stressful exposures, including drug treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive mutability of colorectal cancers in response to targetd therapies</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/adaptive-mutability-of-colorectal-cancers-in-response-to-targetd-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/adaptive-mutability-of-colorectal-cancers-in-response-to-targetd-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The emergence of drug resistance limits the efficacy of targeted therapies in human tumors. The prevalent view is that resistance is a fait accompli: when treatment is initiated, cancers already contain drug-resistant mutant cells. Bacteria exposed to antibiotics transiently increase their mutation rates (adaptive mutability), thus improving the likelihood of survival. We investigated whether human colorectal cancer (CRC) cells likewise exploit adaptive mutability to evade therapeutic pressure. We found that epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)/BRAF inhibition down-regulates mismatch repair (MMR) and homologous recombination DNA-repair genes and concomitantly up-regulates error-prone polymerases in drug-tolerant (persister) cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and analysis of CRISPR–Cas experiments</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/design-and-analysis-of-crispr-cas-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/design-and-analysis-of-crispr-cas-experiments/</guid>
      <description>citation Hanna, R.E., Doench, J.G. Design and analysis of CRISPR–Cas experiments. Nat Biotechnol (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-020-0490-7
Abstract A large and ever-expanding set of CRISPR-Cas systems now enables the rapid and flexible manipulation of genomes in both targeted and large-scale experiments. Numerous software tools and analytical methods have been developed for the design and analysis of CRISPR-Cas experiments, including resources to design optimal guide RNAs for various modes of manipulation and to analyze the results of such experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stemming the tide of drug resistance in cancer</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/07/stemming-the-tide-of-drug-resistance-in-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/07/stemming-the-tide-of-drug-resistance-in-cancer/</guid>
      <description>This is review from nature reviews drug discovery,written by Asher Mullard.
Paul Workman, President of The Institute of Cancer Research (ICR)  This is the biggest problem that we face in cancer drug development,There are a whole slew of different mechanisms that contribute to resistance. We need to be creative and think about how to exploit this biology
 anti-evolution therapy Frederic de Sauvage, a molecular oncologist at Genentech   drugging drug-tolerant persister cells</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-alpha domain </title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/29/z-alpha-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/29/z-alpha-domain/</guid>
      <description>Za bind with Z-DNA as well as RNA  Brown BA 2nd, Lowenhaupt K, Wilbert CM, Hanlon EB, Rich A. The zalpha domain of the editing enzyme dsRNA adenosine deaminase binds left-handed Z-RNA as well as Z-DNA. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97(25):13532‐13536. doi:10.1073/pnas.240464097
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-DNA and human disease</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/29/z-dna-and-human-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/29/z-dna-and-human-disease/</guid>
      <description>Basic knowledge of Z-DNA  Z-DNA is an instable and high energy DNA conformation. In vivo, it requires Za binding protein to maitain the Z-conformation. It was first found in vitro. In vivo, when RNA plolymerase is moving on DNA template, transcription will result in negative supercoiling behind the polymerase, thus facilitating Z-DNA conformation at persmissive regions. In vitro d(GC)n is easy to form Z-DNA, while in vivo, only sepecific sequences can do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 AACR online Day 1</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/27/2020-aacr-online-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/27/2020-aacr-online-day-1/</guid>
      <description>1. Continuous vs Intermittent dosing  The title is &amp;ldquo;SWOG S1320: Improved progression-free survival with continuous compared to intermittent dosing with dabrafenib and trametinib in patients with BRAF mutated melanoma&amp;rdquo;.
  There are several tantalizing preclinical examples to support intermittent or pulsatile therapy but little clinical evidence
  pusatile therapy: another form of intermittent therapy
 2. Combination of IO plus targeted therapy  Clearly works in certain contexts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols for cell atlas projects</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/10/benchmarking-single-cell-rna-sequencing-protocols-for-cell-atlas-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/10/benchmarking-single-cell-rna-sequencing-protocols-for-cell-atlas-projects/</guid>
      <description>TitleBenchmarking single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols for cell atlas projects
CitationMereu, E., Lafzi, A., Moutinho, C. et al. Benchmarking single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols for cell atlas projects. Nat Biotechnol (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-020-0469-4
AbtractSingle-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) is the leading technique for characterizing the transcriptomes of individual cells in a sample. The latest protocols are scalable to thousands of cells and are being used to compile cell atlases of tissues, organs and organisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput identification of genotype-specific cancer vulnerabilities in mixtures of barcoded tumor cell lines</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/06/high-throughput-identification-of-genotype-specific-cancer-vulnerabilities-in-mixtures-of-barcoded-tumor-cell-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/06/high-throughput-identification-of-genotype-specific-cancer-vulnerabilities-in-mixtures-of-barcoded-tumor-cell-lines/</guid>
      <description>TitleHigh-throughput identification of genotype-specific cancer vulnerabilities in mixtures of barcoded tumor cell lines
CitaionYu C, Mannan AM, Yvone GM, et al. High-throughput identification of genotype-specific cancer vulnerabilities in &amp;gt;mixtures of barcoded tumor cell lines. Nat Biotechnol. 2016;34(4):419–423. doi:10.1038/nbt.3460
AbstractHundreds of genetically characterized cell lines are available for the discovery of genotype-specific cancer &amp;gt;vulnerabilities. However, screening large numbers of compounds against large numbers of cell lines is currently &amp;gt;impractical, and such experiments are often difficult to control1-4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>