<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Just for your understanding</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Just for your understanding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences of mitotic slippage for antimicrotubule drug therapy</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/18/consequences-of-mitotic-slippage-for-antimicrotubule-drug-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/18/consequences-of-mitotic-slippage-for-antimicrotubule-drug-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Consequences of mitotic slippage for antimicrotubule drug therapy
Antimitotic agents Microtubule poisons are divided into taxanes and vinca alkaloids depending on how they affect microtubule dynamics. Taxanes are microtubule-stabilising drugs that inhibit the dynamic instability of spindles; examples include commonly-used drugs such as paclitaxel and docetaxel. Vinca alkaloids depolymerise microtubules thereby preventing their attachment to kinetochores; drugs such as vinblastine, vincristine and vinolrelbine fall into this categor
SAC spindle assembly checkpoint The SAC prevents improper chromosome segregation and mitotic exit via inhibition of the anaphase-promoting complex (APC)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mismatch repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/17/mismatch-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/17/mismatch-repair/</guid>
      <description>Mutator A mutation or a mutated gene that increases the basal level of mutation. Such genes often code for proteins that are involved in repairing damaged DNA.A mutator mutant has an increased frequency of spontaneous mutation.
Mut genes Functions in this group include the Dam methylase that identifies the target for repair and enzymes that participate directly or indirectly in the removal of particular types of damage (MutH, -S, -L, and -Y).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Excision Repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/16/base-excision-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/16/base-excision-repair/</guid>
      <description>Glycosylases and lyases. Enzymes that remove bases from DNA
Long-patch pathway Glycosylase action is followed by the endonuclease APE1, which cleaves the polynucleotide chain on the 5′ side. This, in turn, attracts a replication complex that includes DNA polymerase δ/ε and ancillary components. The replication complex performs a short synthesis reaction extending for 2 to 10 nucleotides. The displaced material is removed by the flap endonuclease (FEN1). The enzyme ligase 1 seals the chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error-Prone Repair and Translesion Synthesis</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/16/error-prone-repair-and-translesion-synthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/16/error-prone-repair-and-translesion-synthesis/</guid>
      <description>Damaged DNA that has not been repaired causes prokaryotic DNA polymerase III to stall during replication
  DNA polymerase V (encoded by umuCD) or DNA polymerase IV (encoded by dinB) can synthesize a complement to the damaged strand.
  The DNA synthesized by repair DNA polymerases often has errors in its sequence
  most systems, including uvr-controlled excision repair, do not differ significantly from DNA replication in the frequency of mistakes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/13/dna-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/13/dna-repair/</guid>
      <description>Concept The measured rate of mutation reflects a balance between the number of damaging events occurring in DNA and the number that have been corrected.
The response to damage includes activation and recruitment of repair enzymes; modification of chromatin structure; activation of cell cycle checkpoints; and, in the event of insufficient repair in multicellular organisms, apoptosis
Three type damage  single-base changes : deamination of cytosine to uracil structural distortions/bulky lesions, strand breaks  Direct repair One good example is photoreactivation of pyrimidine dimers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetracycline (Tet) Inducible Expression</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/13/tetracycline-tet-inducible-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/13/tetracycline-tet-inducible-expression/</guid>
      <description>Tet Response Element (TRE) A TRE is 7 repeats of a 19 nucleotide tetracycline operator (tetO) sequence, and is recognized by the tetracycline repressor (tetR). In the endogenous bacterial system, if tetracycline, or one of its analogs like doxycycline, are present, tetR will bind to tetracycline and not to the TRE, permitting transcription.
Tetracycline-dependent promoters are developed by placing a TRE upstream of a minimal promoter.
Tetracycline Off System ( tTA-dependent system) tTA (tetracycline-controlled transactivator) = tetR+VP16</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chromatin-mediated reversible drug tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/a-chromatin-mediated-reversible-drug-tolerant-state-in-cancer-cell-subpopulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/a-chromatin-mediated-reversible-drug-tolerant-state-in-cancer-cell-subpopulations/</guid>
      <description>Citation Sharma, S. V., Lee, D. Y., Li, B., Quinlan, M. P., Takahashi, F., Maheswaran, S., McDermott, U., Azizian, N., Zou, L., Fischbach, M. A., Wong, K. K., Brandstetter, K., Wittner, B., Ramaswamy, S., Classon, M., &amp;amp; Settleman, J. (2010). A chromatin-mediated reversible drug-tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations. Cell, 141(1), 69–80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2010.02.027
Abstract Accumulating evidence implicates heterogeneity within cancer cell populations in the response to stressful exposures, including drug treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive mutability of colorectal cancers in response to targetd therapies</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/adaptive-mutability-of-colorectal-cancers-in-response-to-targetd-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/adaptive-mutability-of-colorectal-cancers-in-response-to-targetd-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The emergence of drug resistance limits the efficacy of targeted therapies in human tumors. The prevalent view is that resistance is a fait accompli: when treatment is initiated, cancers already contain drug-resistant mutant cells. Bacteria exposed to antibiotics transiently increase their mutation rates (adaptive mutability), thus improving the likelihood of survival. We investigated whether human colorectal cancer (CRC) cells likewise exploit adaptive mutability to evade therapeutic pressure. We found that epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)/BRAF inhibition down-regulates mismatch repair (MMR) and homologous recombination DNA-repair genes and concomitantly up-regulates error-prone polymerases in drug-tolerant (persister) cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and analysis of CRISPR–Cas experiments</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/design-and-analysis-of-crispr-cas-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/design-and-analysis-of-crispr-cas-experiments/</guid>
      <description>citation Hanna, R.E., Doench, J.G. Design and analysis of CRISPR–Cas experiments. Nat Biotechnol (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-020-0490-7
Abstract A large and ever-expanding set of CRISPR-Cas systems now enables the rapid and flexible manipulation of genomes in both targeted and large-scale experiments. Numerous software tools and analytical methods have been developed for the design and analysis of CRISPR-Cas experiments, including resources to design optimal guide RNAs for various modes of manipulation and to analyze the results of such experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stemming the tide of drug resistance in cancer</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/07/stemming-the-tide-of-drug-resistance-in-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/07/stemming-the-tide-of-drug-resistance-in-cancer/</guid>
      <description>This is review from nature reviews drug discovery,written by Asher Mullard.
Paul Workman, President of The Institute of Cancer Research (ICR)  This is the biggest problem that we face in cancer drug development,There are a whole slew of different mechanisms that contribute to resistance. We need to be creative and think about how to exploit this biology
 anti-evolution therapy Frederic de Sauvage, a molecular oncologist at Genentech   drugging drug-tolerant persister cells</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Consensus Clustering</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/03/consensus-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/03/consensus-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Consensus clusteringConsensus Clustering is a method that provides quantitative evidence for determining the number and membership of possible clusters within a dataset, such as microarray gene expression.This method has gained popularity in cancer genomics, where new molecular subclasses of disease have been discovered.
The Consensus Clustering methodit involves subsampling from a set of items,such as microarrays, and determines clusterings of specified cluster counts (k).Then, pairwise consensus values, the proportion that two items occupied thesame cluster out of the number of times they occurred in the same subsample,are calculated and stored in a symmetrical consensus matrix for each k</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNV  Terms</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/03/cnv-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/03/cnv-terms/</guid>
      <description>Allele An allele is one of a series of alternative forms (genotypes) at locus, or a specific region of a chromosome. At the DNA level, different alleles have different base sequences.
Allelic fraction The allelic fraction can be defined as the number of times a mutated base is observed, divided by the total number of times any base is observed at the locus.
Allelic fraction is generally applied to a single mutation in a tumor, and thus is distinct from allelic frequency, which examines the frequency of an allele in a population</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R apply function</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/01/r-apply-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/01/r-apply-function/</guid>
      <description>apply() takes Data frame or matrix as an input and gives output in vector, list or array. apply() Function is primarily used to avoid explicit uses of loop constructs. It is the most basic of all collections can be used over a matrice.
This function takes 3 arguments:
apply(X, MARGIN, FUN)
Here:
-x: an array or matrix
-MARGIN: take a value or range between 1 and 2 to define where to apply the function:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-alpha domain </title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/29/z-alpha-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/29/z-alpha-domain/</guid>
      <description>Za bind with Z-DNA as well as RNA  Brown BA 2nd, Lowenhaupt K, Wilbert CM, Hanlon EB, Rich A. The zalpha domain of the editing enzyme dsRNA adenosine deaminase binds left-handed Z-RNA as well as Z-DNA. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97(25):13532‐13536. doi:10.1073/pnas.240464097
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-DNA and human disease</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/29/z-dna-and-human-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/29/z-dna-and-human-disease/</guid>
      <description>Basic knowledge of Z-DNA  Z-DNA is an instable and high energy DNA conformation. In vivo, it requires Za binding protein to maitain the Z-conformation. It was first found in vitro. In vivo, when RNA plolymerase is moving on DNA template, transcription will result in negative supercoiling behind the polymerase, thus facilitating Z-DNA conformation at persmissive regions. In vitro d(GC)n is easy to form Z-DNA, while in vivo, only sepecific sequences can do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 AACR online Day 1</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/27/2020-aacr-online-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/27/2020-aacr-online-day-1/</guid>
      <description>1. Continuous vs Intermittent dosing  The title is &amp;ldquo;SWOG S1320: Improved progression-free survival with continuous compared to intermittent dosing with dabrafenib and trametinib in patients with BRAF mutated melanoma&amp;rdquo;.
  There are several tantalizing preclinical examples to support intermittent or pulsatile therapy but little clinical evidence
  pusatile therapy: another form of intermittent therapy
 2. Combination of IO plus targeted therapy  Clearly works in certain contexts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scientist-2019 Top 10 Innovations</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/23/the-scientist-2019-top-10-innovations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/23/the-scientist-2019-top-10-innovations/</guid>
      <description>This year has proven to be a great one for the life sciences, and the 2010s have been an exciting decade. Here, The Scientist presents the fine-tuned tweaks and brand-new technologies that make up our Top 10 Innovations for 2019.
Refeyn Refeyn One  In 2018, Philipp Kukura at the University of Oxford and his colleagues announced a technology they had developed, called mass photometry, that measures the weight of single molecules by the way they scatter light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toposomerase </title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/19/toposomerase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/19/toposomerase/</guid>
      <description>Supercoil   Supercoiling allows for the compact packing of circular DNA
  Prokaryotes and Eukaryotes usually have negative supercoiled DNA.
  Negative supercoiling is naturally prevalent because negative supercoiling prepares the molecule for processes that require separation of the DNA strands
  RNA polymerase also influence DNA strand to have two different supercoiled directions. The region RNA polymerase has passed forms negative supercoil while the region RNA polymerase that have not passed forms positive supercoil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transponse element-Alu</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/19/transponse-element-alu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/19/transponse-element-alu/</guid>
      <description>Functions and Utility of Alu Jumping Genes
Alu they are the most abundant type of human TE, making up an amazing 10% of the (diploid) human genome. Thus, in a mere 65 million years, these transposons have gone from zero to about 1 million copies per cell! Indeed, part of what makes Alu elements so important is that they are found in nearly every human (and other primate) gene. These elements are spread throughout the genome and occur at varying densities in different loci.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-DNA and Z-RNA in human disease</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/18/z-dna-and-z-rna-in-human-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/18/z-dna-and-z-rna-in-human-disease/</guid>
      <description>It is from one review from
 Herbert A. Z-DNA and Z-RNA in human disease. Commun Biol. 2019;2:7. Published 2019 Jan 7. doi:10.1038/s42003-018-0237-x
 Aicardi-Goutières Syndrome  Aicardi-Goutieres syndrome (AGS) is an inherited encephalopathy that affects newborn infants and usually results in severe mental and physical handicap Loss-of-function mutations in ADAR p150 allow persistent activation of the interferon system by Alu dsRNAs and are causal for Aicardi-Goutières Syndrome
 ADAR   An important inflection point has been the identification of the Z-DNA binding domain named Zα from the dsRNA editing protein ADAR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Regulation of Hepatitis B</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/17/epigenetic-regulation-of-hepatitis-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/17/epigenetic-regulation-of-hepatitis-b/</guid>
      <description>One major reason for failure of HBV treatment is the inability to eradicate or inactivate the viral covalently closed circular DNA (cccDNA), which is a stable episomal form of the viral genome deco- rated with host histones and nonhistone proteins
HBV cccDNA exists in the nucleus as multiple copies of nucleosome-decorated minichromo- somes
five nucleos(t)ide analogues (NUCs), including lamivudine, adefovir, entecavir, telbivudine, and tenofovir, that inhibit HBV reverse transcription
Epigenetic therapy, a novel strategy targeting epigenetic modifications, was first applied successfully to leukemia treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transposons: The Jumping Genes</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/17/transposons-the-jumping-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/17/transposons-the-jumping-genes/</guid>
      <description>Transposable elements, or &amp;ldquo;jumping genes&amp;rdquo;, were first identified by Barbara McClintock more than 50 years ago. Why are transposons so common in eukaryotes, and exactly what do they do?
 Transposable elements (TEs)make up approximately 50% of the human genome and up to 90% of the maize genome
  class 1 TEs (Retrotransposons) and class 2 TEs (DNA Transposons)
 DNA Transposons  All complete or &amp;ldquo;autonomous&amp;rdquo; class 2 TEs encode the protein transposase, which they require for insertion and excision Class 2 TEs are characterized by the presence of terminal inverted repeats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols for cell atlas projects</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/10/benchmarking-single-cell-rna-sequencing-protocols-for-cell-atlas-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/10/benchmarking-single-cell-rna-sequencing-protocols-for-cell-atlas-projects/</guid>
      <description>TitleBenchmarking single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols for cell atlas projects
CitationMereu, E., Lafzi, A., Moutinho, C. et al. Benchmarking single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols for cell atlas projects. Nat Biotechnol (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-020-0469-4
AbtractSingle-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) is the leading technique for characterizing the transcriptomes of individual cells in a sample. The latest protocols are scalable to thousands of cells and are being used to compile cell atlases of tissues, organs and organisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/09/z-nucleic-acid-sensing-triggers-zbp1-dependent-necroptosis-and-inflammation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/09/z-nucleic-acid-sensing-triggers-zbp1-dependent-necroptosis-and-inflammation/</guid>
      <description>TitleZ-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation
CitationJiao, H., Wachsmuth, L., Kumari, S. et al. Z-nucleic-acid sensing triggers ZBP1-dependent necroptosis and inflammation. Nature (2020).https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2129-8
AbtractThe biological function of Z-DNA and Z-RNA, nucleic acid structures with a left-handed double helix, is poorly understood1,2,3.Z-DNA-binding protein 1 (ZBP1; also known as DAI or DLM-1) is a nucleic acid sensor that contains two Zα domains that bind Z-DNA4,5 and Z-RNA6,7,8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput identification of genotype-specific cancer vulnerabilities in mixtures of barcoded tumor cell lines</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/06/high-throughput-identification-of-genotype-specific-cancer-vulnerabilities-in-mixtures-of-barcoded-tumor-cell-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/06/high-throughput-identification-of-genotype-specific-cancer-vulnerabilities-in-mixtures-of-barcoded-tumor-cell-lines/</guid>
      <description>TitleHigh-throughput identification of genotype-specific cancer vulnerabilities in mixtures of barcoded tumor cell lines
CitaionYu C, Mannan AM, Yvone GM, et al. High-throughput identification of genotype-specific cancer vulnerabilities in &amp;gt;mixtures of barcoded tumor cell lines. Nat Biotechnol. 2016;34(4):419–423. doi:10.1038/nbt.3460
AbstractHundreds of genetically characterized cell lines are available for the discovery of genotype-specific cancer &amp;gt;vulnerabilities. However, screening large numbers of compounds against large numbers of cell lines is currently &amp;gt;impractical, and such experiments are often difficult to control1-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News 04062020</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/06/04062020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/06/04062020/</guid>
      <description>Today COVID-19: U.S. at a Glance  Total cases: 330,891 Total deaths: 8,910 Jurisdictions reporting cases: 55 (50 states, District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the U.S. Virgin Islands)  Houston&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 peak may happen earlier than expected  Today, the @HoustonHealth is reporting 402 positive cases for the City of Houston, bringing the total to 1,145. The 402 &amp;gt;cases is because of a backlog of results going back to mid-March that are just now being reported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News 04052020</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/05/04052020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/05/04052020/</guid>
      <description>google adsense review 结果很伤人 前几天尝试一下申请google adsense，把代码加入到我的blog中，让google 来进行审查。今天终于结果出来， Valuable inventory: no content。开始没有看懂是什么结果，后来查证后，其实就是你的website 有用的page基本没有。 我没法收录你的page，你还用什么google AdSense，继续努力吧。
今天开始每天一篇日记，夹杂写一些英文的代码类文章，努力提高原创文章的数量。当初被hugo吸引，静态网站生成器，看了Yihui Xie 做的blogdown + github + netlify,三下五除二做了这么一个网页，就放在那里。
疫情期间，放假在家，又开始学习用R提取数据并作图，接着又把这个网站的项目拾起来了
加油，写完那些没有完成的blog 翻了翻以前的blog，好惭愧。有些只有title，没有内容。不知道那时候的自己在想什么。 难怪goodle adsense 没有通过你的申请。你这是个有模有样的网站吗，显然不是。
认识到自己的错了吗？知道了就要改正！！！
还可以谢谢小朋友的故事 突然想到了这个话题，这个小朋友处在语言发育期和准备独立成长的时期，每天都有新的事情发生，有趣的事情发生，写下来。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Approach Template</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/03/research-approach-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/03/research-approach-template/</guid>
      <description>Approach Template: R01
&amp;lt;1-2 sentences&amp;gt;“Specific Aim 1: To &amp;hellip;” List your first Specific Aim. This is a major heading so Boldit. Copy exactly from the Specific Aims page.
&amp;lt;1-2 paragraphs&amp;gt; Begin by reiterating the premise behind this specific aim (Rationale). Brieflyremind your reviewers what you are studying, reiterate your hypothesis, thesignificance, and what you hope to achieve.
&amp;lt;1-2 paragraphs&amp;gt; Briefly describe any background necessary to understand the context of theSpecific Aim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add Google Adsense and Analytics to a Hugo website</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/02/how-to-add-google-adsense-and-analytics-to-a-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/02/how-to-add-google-adsense-and-analytics-to-a-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>HUGO is a great static website generator.
In this website, the XMIN theme is used.Prepration:
you have a google account and and login the google adsense.
Then you will get the script specific for you.
copy your adsense script.
insert into the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; label of the index of your website.
when you fnished step 2 and google will auto check you website.if they found your script then you can go to next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visting Doctor English Sentences </title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/01/visting-doctor-english-sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/01/visting-doctor-english-sentences/</guid>
      <description>一般病情:  He feels headache, nausea and vomiting. (他觉得头痛、恶心和想吐。)
He is under the weather. (他不舒服，生病了。)
He began to feel unusually tired. (他感到反常的疲倦。)
He feels light-headed. (他觉得头晕。)
She has been shut-in for a few days. (她生病在家几天了。)
Her head is pounding. (她头痛。)
His symptoms include loss of appetite, weight loss, excessive fatigue, fever and chills. (他的症状包括没有食欲、体重减轻、非常疲倦、发烧和发冷。)
He feels exhausted or fatigued most of the time. (他大部份时间都觉得非常疲倦。)
He has been lacking in energy for some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does your cell line work?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</guid>
      <description>My experience When doing the PhD thesis project, I want to detect the ROS-related genes expression by q-PCR. Nine sets of primers were used but only one of them had a positive result. The left eight genes were negtive in the cell line most colleagues used. It seemed impossible but it happened.
In the beginning, I suspected the primers were not right or in bad quality. Another eight new sets of primers were ordered but I still got negtive result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between macrophage and dendritic cell</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/03/what-is-the-difference-between-macrophage-and-dendritic-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/03/what-is-the-difference-between-macrophage-and-dendritic-cell/</guid>
      <description>ABsTRACT  The mononuclear phagocyte system (MPS) has historically been categorized into monocytes, dendritic cells and macrophages on the basis of functional and phenotypical characteristics. However, considering that these characteristics are often overlapping, the distinction between and classification of these cell types has been challenging.In this Opinion article, we propose a unified nomenclature for the MPS. We suggest that these cells can be classified primarily by their ontogeny and secondarily by their location, function and phenotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain tumor center in USA</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</guid>
      <description>The brain tumor center in the USA is listed in
http://abc2.org/guidance/find-care
1 NCI cancer research center neuro-oncology branch https://ccr.cancer.gov/Neuro-Oncology-Branch
2 Dana Farber Center for neuro-oncology https://www.dana-farber.org/center-for-neuro-oncology/clinical-research-and-trials/
3 Duke University The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center https://tischbraintumorcenter.duke.edu/program-members/
Please find more information about brain tumore ccenter in USA here
When choosing a brain tumor treatment center, consider:
 How many brain tumor patients the center treats each year Whether the center offers access to specialists, such as a neuro-oncologist and radiation oncologist Whether the center is in your insurance plan’s covered network  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome Editing- crispr-cas9</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/genome-editing-crispr-cas9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/genome-editing-crispr-cas9/</guid>
      <description>Genome editing Genome editing (also called gene editing) is a group of technologies that give scientists the ability to change an organism&amp;rsquo;s DNA.These technologies allow genetic material to be added, removed, or altered at particular locations in the genome. Several approaches to genome editing have been developed. A recent one is known as CRISPR-Cas9, which is short for clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats and CRISPR-associated protein 9. The CRISPR-Cas9 system has generated a lot of excitement in the scientific community because it is faster, cheaper, more accurate, and more efficient than other existing genome editing methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem cell in U87</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</guid>
      <description>Are there stem cells in the cell line cultures? Yes, some cell lines have.
U87 is one gliblastoma cell line containing stem cell. You can isolate them following the protocol below.
Lacopino F, Angelucci C, Piacentini R, Biamonte F, Mangiola A, et al. (2014) Isolation of Cancer Stem Cells from Three Human Glioblastoma Cell Lines: Characterization of Two Selected Clones. PLOS ONE 9(8): e105166. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0105166
 All the monolayer growing cell lines, U373 (22–25th passage), U87-MG (52–55th passage) and LI (93–95th passage) were seeded at a density of 100,000 cells/ml, in a defined serum-free medium, DMEM/F12, supplemented with antibiotics (penicillin 100 IU/ml, streptomycin 100 µm/ml), HEPES (10 mM), glutamine (2 mM), glucose (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transplatation Immnunology</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/31/transplatation-immnunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/31/transplatation-immnunology/</guid>
      <description>Background Why I started to read transplatation immnunology?
I&amp;rsquo;m trying to kill glioblastoma with allogenic macropahges.
Here I recommended immunopaedia, which is supported by International Union of Immnunological Societies。
Introduction   In a clinical setting, the term transplantation generally refers to the transfer or replacement of cells, tissues, or organs from one individual to another.
  In the human, with the exception of transplantation of one’s own tissues, where the recognition of ‘‘self’’ components evokes no immune response, the transplantation of all other tissues, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine catagory in Walmart</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/28/wine-catagory-in-walmart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/28/wine-catagory-in-walmart/</guid>
      <description>America is the fourth biggest wine country in the world just after France, Italy and Spain. It has a long history and rich culture of wine
The main areas are Oregon and California.
Below are the names of grapes used to brew the wine.
Pinot Noirc 黑皮诺 Pinot Girls 灰皮诺 Cabernet sauvigon 赤霞珠 Merlot 梅洛 Rhone Vally 罗纳河谷 Syrah 西拉 Grenache 歌海娜 Petit Verdot 味儿多 Petite Sirah 小西拉 Mourvedre 慕合怀特 Chardonnay 霞多丽 Tempranillo 丹魄 Zinfandel 仙粉黛 Sauvigon Blanc 长相思 Riesling 雷司令 Cabernet Franc p品丽珠 Montepulciano 蒙特布查诺 Sangiovese 桑娇维塞 Barbera 巴贝拉 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microscope usage</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/27/microscope-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/27/microscope-usage/</guid>
      <description>background Lots of slides were stained by immunohistochemisty, but i can not get good pictures. Today I recognized my misusage of microscope with my supervisor&amp;rsquo;s help.
How should I take picutres withe microscope to get clear result? For the immunohistochemisty staining with DAB and couterstaining with hematoxilin.
At the beginning, I tried the bright field with Ph1 and it was wrong. The picutures were very urgly and seemed not like the real condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell apoptosis signaling pathway</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</guid>
      <description>Background I reviewed several manuscripts titled liket &amp;ldquo;XX promotes oxidative stress and induces apoptosis in YY cells&amp;rdquo;.
Here, &amp;ldquo;XX&amp;rdquo; can be any chemical from nature product or synthezed in the lab. &amp;ldquo;YY&amp;rdquo; can be caner cells, nenron cells and various cells. They may be cell lines or primary cells. By combination, hundreds of paper can be produced. How do you evaluate them in the perspective of basic reserch or drug development?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The index to evaluate gene expression in RNA-seq</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/the-index-to-evaluate-gene-expression-in-rna-seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/the-index-to-evaluate-gene-expression-in-rna-seq/</guid>
      <description>Backgroud One commen quesion is wether one certain gene is expresed in one cell line or tissue or organ in human or mouse. for wet lab, qPCR or antibody-based assays can be performed with commercial antibodies. if no antibody is available, How should we do and this data is indispensable.
RPKM, FKPM and TPM  RPKM (Reads Per Kilobase Million) or FPKM (Fragments Per Kilobase Million). However, TPM (Transcripts Per Kilobase Million) is now becoming quite popular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>flow cytometry data analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/flow-cytometry-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/flow-cytometry-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>What is flow cytometry?Flow cytometry is a widely used method for analyzing the expression of cell surface and intracellular molecules, characterizing and defining different cell types in a heterogeneous cell population, assessing the purity of isolated subpopulations and analyzing cell size and volume. It allows simultaneous multi-parameter analysis of single cells.
Why is flow cytometry data important?It is predominantly used to measure fluorescence intensity produced by fluorescent-labeled antibodies detecting proteins, or ligands that bind to specific cell-associated molecules such as propidium iodide binding to DNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rtsne </title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/rtsne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/rtsne/</guid>
      <description>Why we need tSNE?If you have worked with a dataset before with a lot of features, you can fathom how difficult it is to understand or explore the relationships between the features. Not only it makes the EDA process difficult but also affects the machine learning model’s performance since the chances are that you might overfit your model or violate some of the assumptions of the algorithm, like the independence of features in linear regression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why cancer happens?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</guid>
      <description>The nature of cancer is abnormal proliferation of cells made of our organ, tissue and body.What drives physiology cells into crazy demons? Are genetic facrors or enviroment risks canse the transition of cells from health to disease?
According to modern biological perspective, genome mutation results in the cell transformation.
Cell changes and cancer  All cancers begin in cells. Our bodies are made up of more than a hundred million million (100,000,000,000,000) cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing test in Chinese</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/04/writing-test-in-chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/04/writing-test-in-chinese/</guid>
      <description>主页显示正常 markdown 标记正常。 二级页面显示正常。 需要解决的问题： 设置字体，字号以及后续排版</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuro-Oncology</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/03/neuro-oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/03/neuro-oncology/</guid>
      <description>Neuro OncologyIt is the officical journal of the Society for Neuro-Oncology and published monthly from Jan.2010.
The current impact factor is 10.091 and 5-year impact factor is 9.053
About the editorKenneth Aldape is the interim editor-in-chief. His research area is genomic and epigenomic alterations in brain tumors, &amp;gt;including glioma and meningioma. We characterize the biology of specific genomic alterations and how they contribute to &amp;gt;the molecular pathogenesis and treatment resistance of aggressive brain tumors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCGA Database</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/02/tcga-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/02/tcga-database/</guid>
      <description>What is TCGA  The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA), a landmark cancer genomics program, molecular characterized over 20,000 primary &amp;gt;cancer and matched normal samples spanning 33 cancer types. This joint effort between the National Cancer Institute and &amp;gt;the National Human Genome Research Institute began in 2006, bringing together researchers from diverse disciplines and &amp;gt;multiple institutions.
 How to access TCGA data  Access TCGA data through the Genomic Data Commons Data Portal, along with web-based analysis and visualization tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>