<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer on Just for your understanding</title>
    <link>/tags/cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cancer on Just for your understanding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Does your cell line work?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</guid>
      <description>My experience When doing the PhD thesis project, I want to detect the ROS-related genes expression by q-PCR. Nine sets of primers were used but only one of them had a positive result. The left eight genes were negtive in the cell line most colleagues used. It seemed impossible but it happened.
In the beginning, I suspected the primers were not right or in bad quality. Another eight new sets of primers were ordered but I still got negtive result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain tumor center in USA</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</guid>
      <description>The brain tumor center in the USA is listed in
http://abc2.org/guidance/find-care
1 NCI cancer research center neuro-oncology branch https://ccr.cancer.gov/Neuro-Oncology-Branch
2 Dana Farber Center for neuro-oncology https://www.dana-farber.org/center-for-neuro-oncology/clinical-research-and-trials/
3 Duke University The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center https://tischbraintumorcenter.duke.edu/program-members/
4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome Editing- crispr-cas9</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/genome-editing-crispr-cas9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/genome-editing-crispr-cas9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem cell in U87</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</guid>
      <description>Are there stem cells in the cell line cultures? Yes, some cell lines have.
U87 is one gliblastoma cell line containing stem cell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell apoptosis signaling pathway</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</guid>
      <description>Background I reviewed several manuscripts titled liket &amp;ldquo;XX promotes oxidative stress and induces apoptosis in YY cells&amp;rdquo;.
Here, &amp;ldquo;XX&amp;rdquo; can be any chemical from nature product or synthezed in the lab. &amp;ldquo;YY&amp;rdquo; can be caner cells, nenron cells and various cells. They may be cell lines or primary cells. By combination, hundreds of paper can be produced. How do you evaluate them in the perspective of basic reserch or drug development?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The index to evaluate gene expression in RNA-seq</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/the-index-to-evaluate-gene-expression-in-rna-seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/the-index-to-evaluate-gene-expression-in-rna-seq/</guid>
      <description>Backgroud One commen quesion is wether one certain gene is expresed in one cell line or tissue or organ in human or mouse. for wet lab, qPCR or antibody-based assays can be performed with commercial antibodies. if no antibody is available, How should we do and this data is indispensable.
Database will help you </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why cancer happens?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</guid>
      <description>The nature of cancer is abnormal proliferation of cells made of our organ, tissue and body.What drives physiology cells into crazy demons? Are genetic facrors or enviroment risks canse the transition of cells from health to disease?
According to modern biological perspective, genome mutation results in the cell transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCGA Database</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/02/tcga-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/02/tcga-database/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>