<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer on Just for your understanding</title>
    <link>/tags/cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cancer on Just for your understanding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences of mitotic slippage for antimicrotubule drug therapy</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/18/consequences-of-mitotic-slippage-for-antimicrotubule-drug-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/18/consequences-of-mitotic-slippage-for-antimicrotubule-drug-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Consequences of mitotic slippage for antimicrotubule drug therapy
Antimitotic agents Microtubule poisons are divided into taxanes and vinca alkaloids depending on how they affect microtubule dynamics. Taxanes are microtubule-stabilising drugs that inhibit the dynamic instability of spindles; examples include commonly-used drugs such as paclitaxel and docetaxel. Vinca alkaloids depolymerise microtubules thereby preventing their attachment to kinetochores; drugs such as vinblastine, vincristine and vinolrelbine fall into this categor
SAC spindle assembly checkpoint The SAC prevents improper chromosome segregation and mitotic exit via inhibition of the anaphase-promoting complex (APC)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mismatch repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/17/mismatch-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/17/mismatch-repair/</guid>
      <description>Mutator A mutation or a mutated gene that increases the basal level of mutation. Such genes often code for proteins that are involved in repairing damaged DNA.A mutator mutant has an increased frequency of spontaneous mutation.
Mut genes Functions in this group include the Dam methylase that identifies the target for repair and enzymes that participate directly or indirectly in the removal of particular types of damage (MutH, -S, -L, and -Y).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Excision Repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/16/base-excision-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/16/base-excision-repair/</guid>
      <description>Glycosylases and lyases. Enzymes that remove bases from DNA
Long-patch pathway Glycosylase action is followed by the endonuclease APE1, which cleaves the polynucleotide chain on the 5′ side. This, in turn, attracts a replication complex that includes DNA polymerase δ/ε and ancillary components. The replication complex performs a short synthesis reaction extending for 2 to 10 nucleotides. The displaced material is removed by the flap endonuclease (FEN1). The enzyme ligase 1 seals the chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error-Prone Repair and Translesion Synthesis</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/16/error-prone-repair-and-translesion-synthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/16/error-prone-repair-and-translesion-synthesis/</guid>
      <description>Damaged DNA that has not been repaired causes prokaryotic DNA polymerase III to stall during replication
  DNA polymerase V (encoded by umuCD) or DNA polymerase IV (encoded by dinB) can synthesize a complement to the damaged strand.
  The DNA synthesized by repair DNA polymerases often has errors in its sequence
  most systems, including uvr-controlled excision repair, do not differ significantly from DNA replication in the frequency of mistakes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA repair</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/13/dna-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/13/dna-repair/</guid>
      <description>Concept The measured rate of mutation reflects a balance between the number of damaging events occurring in DNA and the number that have been corrected.
The response to damage includes activation and recruitment of repair enzymes; modification of chromatin structure; activation of cell cycle checkpoints; and, in the event of insufficient repair in multicellular organisms, apoptosis
Three type damage  single-base changes : deamination of cytosine to uracil structural distortions/bulky lesions, strand breaks  Direct repair One good example is photoreactivation of pyrimidine dimers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chromatin-mediated reversible drug tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/a-chromatin-mediated-reversible-drug-tolerant-state-in-cancer-cell-subpopulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/a-chromatin-mediated-reversible-drug-tolerant-state-in-cancer-cell-subpopulations/</guid>
      <description>Citation Sharma, S. V., Lee, D. Y., Li, B., Quinlan, M. P., Takahashi, F., Maheswaran, S., McDermott, U., Azizian, N., Zou, L., Fischbach, M. A., Wong, K. K., Brandstetter, K., Wittner, B., Ramaswamy, S., Classon, M., &amp;amp; Settleman, J. (2010). A chromatin-mediated reversible drug-tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations. Cell, 141(1), 69–80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2010.02.027
Abstract Accumulating evidence implicates heterogeneity within cancer cell populations in the response to stressful exposures, including drug treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive mutability of colorectal cancers in response to targetd therapies</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/adaptive-mutability-of-colorectal-cancers-in-response-to-targetd-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/adaptive-mutability-of-colorectal-cancers-in-response-to-targetd-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The emergence of drug resistance limits the efficacy of targeted therapies in human tumors. The prevalent view is that resistance is a fait accompli: when treatment is initiated, cancers already contain drug-resistant mutant cells. Bacteria exposed to antibiotics transiently increase their mutation rates (adaptive mutability), thus improving the likelihood of survival. We investigated whether human colorectal cancer (CRC) cells likewise exploit adaptive mutability to evade therapeutic pressure. We found that epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)/BRAF inhibition down-regulates mismatch repair (MMR) and homologous recombination DNA-repair genes and concomitantly up-regulates error-prone polymerases in drug-tolerant (persister) cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and analysis of CRISPR–Cas experiments</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/08/design-and-analysis-of-crispr-cas-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/08/design-and-analysis-of-crispr-cas-experiments/</guid>
      <description>citation Hanna, R.E., Doench, J.G. Design and analysis of CRISPR–Cas experiments. Nat Biotechnol (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-020-0490-7
Abstract A large and ever-expanding set of CRISPR-Cas systems now enables the rapid and flexible manipulation of genomes in both targeted and large-scale experiments. Numerous software tools and analytical methods have been developed for the design and analysis of CRISPR-Cas experiments, including resources to design optimal guide RNAs for various modes of manipulation and to analyze the results of such experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stemming the tide of drug resistance in cancer</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/07/stemming-the-tide-of-drug-resistance-in-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/07/stemming-the-tide-of-drug-resistance-in-cancer/</guid>
      <description>This is review from nature reviews drug discovery,written by Asher Mullard.
Paul Workman, President of The Institute of Cancer Research (ICR)  This is the biggest problem that we face in cancer drug development,There are a whole slew of different mechanisms that contribute to resistance. We need to be creative and think about how to exploit this biology
 anti-evolution therapy Frederic de Sauvage, a molecular oncologist at Genentech   drugging drug-tolerant persister cells</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-alpha domain </title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/29/z-alpha-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/29/z-alpha-domain/</guid>
      <description>Za bind with Z-DNA as well as RNA  Brown BA 2nd, Lowenhaupt K, Wilbert CM, Hanlon EB, Rich A. The zalpha domain of the editing enzyme dsRNA adenosine deaminase binds left-handed Z-RNA as well as Z-DNA. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97(25):13532‐13536. doi:10.1073/pnas.240464097
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-DNA and human disease</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/29/z-dna-and-human-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/29/z-dna-and-human-disease/</guid>
      <description>Basic knowledge of Z-DNA  Z-DNA is an instable and high energy DNA conformation. In vivo, it requires Za binding protein to maitain the Z-conformation. It was first found in vitro. In vivo, when RNA plolymerase is moving on DNA template, transcription will result in negative supercoiling behind the polymerase, thus facilitating Z-DNA conformation at persmissive regions. In vitro d(GC)n is easy to form Z-DNA, while in vivo, only sepecific sequences can do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 AACR online Day 1</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/27/2020-aacr-online-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/27/2020-aacr-online-day-1/</guid>
      <description>1. Continuous vs Intermittent dosing  The title is &amp;ldquo;SWOG S1320: Improved progression-free survival with continuous compared to intermittent dosing with dabrafenib and trametinib in patients with BRAF mutated melanoma&amp;rdquo;.
  There are several tantalizing preclinical examples to support intermittent or pulsatile therapy but little clinical evidence
  pusatile therapy: another form of intermittent therapy
 2. Combination of IO plus targeted therapy  Clearly works in certain contexts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does your cell line work?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/09/does-your-cell-line-work/</guid>
      <description>My experience When doing the PhD thesis project, I want to detect the ROS-related genes expression by q-PCR. Nine sets of primers were used but only one of them had a positive result. The left eight genes were negtive in the cell line most colleagues used. It seemed impossible but it happened.
In the beginning, I suspected the primers were not right or in bad quality. Another eight new sets of primers were ordered but I still got negtive result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain tumor center in USA</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/02/brain-tumor-center-in-usa/</guid>
      <description>The brain tumor center in the USA is listed in
http://abc2.org/guidance/find-care
1 NCI cancer research center neuro-oncology branch https://ccr.cancer.gov/Neuro-Oncology-Branch
2 Dana Farber Center for neuro-oncology https://www.dana-farber.org/center-for-neuro-oncology/clinical-research-and-trials/
3 Duke University The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center https://tischbraintumorcenter.duke.edu/program-members/
Please find more information about brain tumore ccenter in USA here
When choosing a brain tumor treatment center, consider:
 How many brain tumor patients the center treats each year Whether the center offers access to specialists, such as a neuro-oncologist and radiation oncologist Whether the center is in your insurance plan’s covered network  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome Editing- crispr-cas9</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/genome-editing-crispr-cas9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/genome-editing-crispr-cas9/</guid>
      <description>Genome editing Genome editing (also called gene editing) is a group of technologies that give scientists the ability to change an organism&amp;rsquo;s DNA.These technologies allow genetic material to be added, removed, or altered at particular locations in the genome. Several approaches to genome editing have been developed. A recent one is known as CRISPR-Cas9, which is short for clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats and CRISPR-associated protein 9. The CRISPR-Cas9 system has generated a lot of excitement in the scientific community because it is faster, cheaper, more accurate, and more efficient than other existing genome editing methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem cell in U87</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/01/stem-cell-in-u87/</guid>
      <description>Are there stem cells in the cell line cultures? Yes, some cell lines have.
U87 is one gliblastoma cell line containing stem cell. You can isolate them following the protocol below.
Lacopino F, Angelucci C, Piacentini R, Biamonte F, Mangiola A, et al. (2014) Isolation of Cancer Stem Cells from Three Human Glioblastoma Cell Lines: Characterization of Two Selected Clones. PLOS ONE 9(8): e105166. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0105166
 All the monolayer growing cell lines, U373 (22–25th passage), U87-MG (52–55th passage) and LI (93–95th passage) were seeded at a density of 100,000 cells/ml, in a defined serum-free medium, DMEM/F12, supplemented with antibiotics (penicillin 100 IU/ml, streptomycin 100 µm/ml), HEPES (10 mM), glutamine (2 mM), glucose (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell apoptosis signaling pathway</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/cell-apoptosis-signaling-pathway/</guid>
      <description>Background I reviewed several manuscripts titled liket &amp;ldquo;XX promotes oxidative stress and induces apoptosis in YY cells&amp;rdquo;.
Here, &amp;ldquo;XX&amp;rdquo; can be any chemical from nature product or synthezed in the lab. &amp;ldquo;YY&amp;rdquo; can be caner cells, nenron cells and various cells. They may be cell lines or primary cells. By combination, hundreds of paper can be produced. How do you evaluate them in the perspective of basic reserch or drug development?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The index to evaluate gene expression in RNA-seq</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/21/the-index-to-evaluate-gene-expression-in-rna-seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/21/the-index-to-evaluate-gene-expression-in-rna-seq/</guid>
      <description>Backgroud One commen quesion is wether one certain gene is expresed in one cell line or tissue or organ in human or mouse. for wet lab, qPCR or antibody-based assays can be performed with commercial antibodies. if no antibody is available, How should we do and this data is indispensable.
RPKM, FKPM and TPM  RPKM (Reads Per Kilobase Million) or FPKM (Fragments Per Kilobase Million). However, TPM (Transcripts Per Kilobase Million) is now becoming quite popular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why cancer happens?</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/15/why-cancer-happens/</guid>
      <description>The nature of cancer is abnormal proliferation of cells made of our organ, tissue and body.What drives physiology cells into crazy demons? Are genetic facrors or enviroment risks canse the transition of cells from health to disease?
According to modern biological perspective, genome mutation results in the cell transformation.
Cell changes and cancer  All cancers begin in cells. Our bodies are made up of more than a hundred million million (100,000,000,000,000) cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCGA Database</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/02/tcga-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/02/tcga-database/</guid>
      <description>What is TCGA  The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA), a landmark cancer genomics program, molecular characterized over 20,000 primary &amp;gt;cancer and matched normal samples spanning 33 cancer types. This joint effort between the National Cancer Institute and &amp;gt;the National Human Genome Research Institute began in 2006, bringing together researchers from diverse disciplines and &amp;gt;multiple institutions.
 How to access TCGA data  Access TCGA data through the Genomic Data Commons Data Portal, along with web-based analysis and visualization tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>