<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunology on Just for your understanding</title>
    <link>/tags/immunology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immunology on Just for your understanding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/immunology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between macrophage and dendritic cell</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/03/what-is-the-difference-between-macrophage-and-dendritic-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/03/what-is-the-difference-between-macrophage-and-dendritic-cell/</guid>
      <description>ABsTRACT  The mononuclear phagocyte system (MPS) has historically been categorized into monocytes, dendritic cells and macrophages on the basis of functional and phenotypical characteristics. However, considering that these characteristics are often overlapping, the distinction between and classification of these cell types has been challenging.In this Opinion article, we propose a unified nomenclature for the MPS. We suggest that these cells can be classified primarily by their ontogeny and secondarily by their location, function and phenotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transplatation Immnunology</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/31/transplatation-immnunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/31/transplatation-immnunology/</guid>
      <description>Background Why I started to read transplatation immnunology?
I&amp;rsquo;m trying to kill glioblastoma with allogenic macropahges.
Here I recommended immunopaedia, which is supported by International Union of Immnunological Societies。
Introduction   In a clinical setting, the term transplantation generally refers to the transfer or replacement of cells, tissues, or organs from one individual to another.
  In the human, with the exception of transplantation of one’s own tissues, where the recognition of ‘‘self’’ components evokes no immune response, the transplantation of all other tissues, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>